Just because it's very depressing, he gave
a really good talk about how to have
negative emotions, and the whole morning was about
how to have negative thoughts. That's why I
wanted to take a break from the hunger.
So I'd like to go into the explanation
of the structure of the design courses
because if you're going to be an Asian master,
behind your mind you need to have the whole
structure of all 18 fundamental courses.
So we've already done four, and I'd like to
continue with that. Maybe we'll do three or
four more today, which
are other courses that we talked about
in another one. In each course, keep one thing in mind:
we're talking about how it flows, why one
course comes before and why this course
comes after, where it fits into
how it flows,
which of the five themes is which, and when
the four schools... So we need to
talk a little bit about the content, which is another
thing that I think you won't remember
very well.
The book, the book, and which commentary? I don't
just choose the poem. They're
poems; they're very difficult and need
an explanation,
so I take the best of the best.
Which commentary do we
use? Okay,
just before I do that, I
was looking at the course and I thought,
for me, it's very interesting
how the five themes flow.
First you start with the lowest school
and then the highest school, with parties
at the highest school in case you die
halfway through the street course. So that's why you should
start with maybe
the highest one, because many
die in 25 years. Many die,
clearly. My house started with 60 young people
and only 4 of us finished, and that's very typical.
We had 4 gay guys who graduated from my
class and the rest died or
left or couldn't do it. So how do
you arrange the order? What is the order? And it's
a bit unexpected and needs an
explanation. Accident, and it was put in the
document, in your manual.
In fact, some of the manuals
aren't finished. If you don't determine
where you read it, because they aren't...
We're going to try to finish everything in three
courses, in three trainings. So
at the end of this year, you'll have
all the policies of Asia and you'll
have all three courses and you'll
have all the information, all the
structure, blah blah.
So okay, the first thing,
the 75-page text
called Jewels of Achievements,
written by dictation from Maitreya, her
secretary.
If you know the...  The story of the dogs in the
lion dance, you know how it happened, and so there are
five great books of Maitreya,
and this, we studied it first.
In fact, what are the five themes? And the
Perfection of Wisdom, which is
number four, which is what school?
What school?
The path gave me more work, and in fact,
also the books of Us and Gas,
really, are just the school, only
this life. So we listened to that, we
studied that. I describe it. It's been 27 years
since I described these courses. It's a
way of writing the Perfection of
Wisdom, which means lower to the
scriptures
and being a very vast encyclopedia of
all, of everything beyond all the
teachings of Lewenza Adba, except the
exact concept, totally correct
presentations of emptiness. Everything
else is there, it's very similar, or
navigated in life, weapons, like all
the fundamental things that must be
free. There are hundreds of ideas in play
in the lower middle school, the [ __ ] of
realizations written by Next
Wood, which is a very good source, and everyone
agrees that they are already doubtful, but that
nothing else is there, but nobody sees it
because they have no seeds and they don't
recognize it, then
in slaves  And they are very close, what's coming is going to
come, they are very close
to that body of literature, we are 12
years in the game, the first 12 years, so
the first thing you study is
monastery, 75 pages, the normal school students,
normally the humorists, before you are
15, it's
very beautiful because we children have
12 schools and every night
around this time the children go out onto the
porch, onto the porch
[Music]
and it's very beautiful because they try to
do it louder than the children from the
abbot's house, it's that in the monastery you can't
take a nap at that hour because the
whole monastery is there, 15 and there are
children at 15 years old shouting,
this is very beautiful, it
's a custom of reciting a mantra,
saying it very loudly so that the
spirits hear it, it's a tradition
not to whisper your mantras but to say them
very clearly so that all the spirits
in the room hear it, so I
think this is the theory that the
children shout so that another monk will
leave, so I was two years there
after that, which is logic, what does
logic mean, after this we are going to
give  A teaching of emptiness, then you
spend four years in the highest middle school, that's
the number, year
number 13 to year number 16, 6 and click
fixing, you spend 4 years fixing the
teachings of emptiness. Technically, you
're studying the book "
Entering the Middle Way" by the track kit,
which is a great commentary in Yunnan,
the book "Wisdom" by Nagar Gym, and these
books have a
monastic associate book. Their
commentaries that we use are very large.
For the first 12 years, there are about 14,000
pages of commentaries by one author. So
each monastery has its own
commentary,
and normally there are two different ones.
One is called "Time in Touch," which means like a
review of all the topics. It
means analysis.
In both books, they are written in a
debate style; there are always two
people debating, and that makes the
student prepared. So in
fact, we don't study;
we study the first 12 years based
on 8 books of our ministry. They are
very large.
And then when we reach the second
topic, which is the highest middle school
called the Middle Way, which from Chile, there is
a Chilean again, and in  There's a
review, a quick intuition, and there's a
deeper understanding. We're both
incredibly beautiful. We're going to
translate them. We don't have time. They're
incredibly beautiful,
and we use Hindu commentaries on each one. And we use
those too, so we don't mediate apart from the
two monastic texts. Whatever we
use,
if you're a serious student, and that's it, you not
only study the two monastic books,
but you're also capable of
explanations
of vanity, called the illumination of
true thought, which is what
Chandra Chitin meant. Violence is what
we're translating. It was the team from the
direction; we're barely halfway through. It took us
two years, and it's 750 pages. Segovia,
until then, we're going to finish 1500
pages, and we did it in five years. And that's
the highest commentary for
most. The subject
can be studied carefully. If
getting to this subject required, well,
special teachings from my
super scripture teacher. That
journey has taken a while. We've been on it for
eight years now.
We started with four or five of my
friends, and all of them, now not families,
quit. So for me, it's something
because I had debates with the greatest.
Masters at zero
and he is an incredible teacher he
gave me and we spent two years in
binary,
binary 17 and 18, we spent in Vinaya
also the
ethical morality that his book is binary, his work
written by a human being called with
a potato
in each monastery has health
comment I am interested I
enjoy talking about these things it
is probably boring for you
but I don't care
Thompson Sunday means a summer in a
plane
a summary of all binary like a
poem and you learn it, you memorize it, you
enlist, he is translating one of those
chanting industry jokes, he is
translating the one that is smaller and a
community but usually they are
longer than the memorizing ones
and if you really want to get into it there
are incredible comments
this comment is not very famous but it is
the best to
translate here I worked on it for like five
years with someone but they quit and
took all the recordings, right? So
anyway,
a question doesn't come to mind when you were, I mean, you
study binary until year
17 and friends, man, and then what do
mobiles do? They
don't study
250 votes for a monk and  304 for a
death
because they spent 17 years of master's degree,
start selling before they were given
the vows, and this is another detail of the
courses in Greece that I must mention, and it is
the role that
the teacher of your school means, which is like your
money and does not give up, which is to teach the
children to put on their habits and care
when we started in the monastery, we
were all refugees
and all the children were in the same
room and we did not have enough food and
so the children would get infected, they had
these wounds and they would get infected,
the gay workhouse, the home that
has been a girl
for 500 years, they should thank him at least a little bit,
a mobile phone that took care of them,
his job is to feed them and find
the money and give them clothes, so if his
job and what the monks do and
normally that person in your life is
like an addition to the course of the gay
monk photos and cinema, my personal experience,
and that is one of the 253 don't do it, and
then how to learn these vows in the
monastery, well, they can't
sit with you and teach you the
master's vows, that's what he did  He made a
commentary on freedom, not called a
water show, and wrote a
2000-page commentary on the vows of monks and
nuns. It's incredible, extraordinary. He lived
before they were capable, so we studied
other traditions. It's a charge, and it's an
incredible commentary, and we still use it. I use it
almost daily when I'm
teaching Vinaya. It's extraordinary.
So, yes, I was in my
training, in my vows, as soon as I
became a monk, but I was already 30. So, I
was very fortunate because I had a
chance to do all the
bad things before this foundation. It's that I did
everything really well, and it's not like in the
old days you couldn't become a monk
until 30, like you. You didn't become a
monk until 30, you didn't have your
complete monks' vows,
and so before, they wanted to take great care of you. It
was a great honor to be a
monk, and many days later in your
life...
So, the answer to your question is,
your teacher teaches you, demonstrates, the
college teaches you all the vows,
telling you what you shouldn't do when you
do it, and it's a very organic way that
all young monks learn
their vows. For example, I can't
take off my monk's robes, I can't just...
Throw them away and step on the melody,
they will step on them, and this goes against
my rules. I have to take them off over
my head. I can't step over
them, and there are many rules.
So you can write a book, you can
write them in a book. If your teacher
hits you once with a rosary, you will
memorize it.
Then you undertake the ancient sources
and learn two boats, the
original incidents. This is a very
important video when you are running an
organization like Diamond Momentary.
As Yang Yimin said, lines, and it means
someone who is someone who
ruined it.
Originally, Buddhism, in Buddhism, you
could drink alcohol. When he could, he
started teaching,
but then a link. If someone got
very drunk and caused problems, I do
n't remember what it was. Project, you
can study it, and thanks to
John's database, you can search for the
PNC. If next to alcohol, they will
give you a million pages in
less than 10 seconds. That's how you
learn the scriptures
with John Brady's database. So
if you ask me right now what the
incident was, I can find it
nearby.  In ten seconds you can search
a million pages in 10,
so in fact the course you're
getting is in many ways, the
information is more accurate, more accurate
because I checked the entire database and
assets, I have access to thousands of books,
10,000 books here, so
you can check things.
[Music]
I like to tell stories, maybe you already noticed,
so I was on a
plane once to hear a teaching
from a lama, and there were many people on the
plane that I didn't know who were going to this
small town to hear this person,
and I was translating The Life Weapon. In
this period, I spent 12 years translating
The Life Weapon, and so I was
working on forgetting, I only reached the
part where Buddha said about the lens and
about alcohol,
and well, I'm going to tell you the story. A
Tibetan said next to me, he was
sitting next to me, I didn't know him, and we were
flying, and he asked for a beer. I
was surprised, and then I thought,
one thing, I
found the part where he said, "
If you sell a drop of alcohol, what
fits on the tip of it, a
big one, no, he said no, no."  Bebas said, "Don't
call yourself a Buddhist,
don't say you're my student. You're not
my student,
you're a very good person. Come on, fine,
but don't say you're my student."
Five more times, how much does it matter to see this
amount of alcohol? Then find
the page, and I said, "Is it true that you
can help me with this page?" And I can't, I can't
understand it. And my son,
and it was very nice, the beer.
Then the 19th, the 20th, towards the exit, we
don't touch, to forget, more precisely, although
in other schools for 18 years until the
19th and 20th we do the life weapon, so
the information there comes out in the
teachings of hunger
and continues to come out of all the books,
but then if you take a life and if you have
a large dose of life weapon in
the first 18 years, but in the year 1920 I
studied known weapon formally, to
tell the truth, when you get there, you already know
like ten monks in your class
and it gets kind of weird because you don't know what
the other times know and they know what they do
n't know, so there can't be
a debate,
the debates get very boring
because you've been with these guys and 18
years and you know he never learned the
Four Truths or didn't learn both,
so you can debate and you'll get
the same answers. So they do
something really cool at the monastery in
two classes, like these days. They bring you to
the next class, he's the one who gets promoted, and
then they lose a year.
Unfortunately, we're the
lowest class, so we skip a year. We weren't there
because there was no
one left to debate with. There are only like
five guys above
us. So we combine the two
classes, and our meals... we didn't have any
trouble with the interpretation. So I went
with him, and he
taught me this for a couple of years. But that's how
people don't take it. So the gases
store the knowledge in case something happens
at the monastery. So what topic?
We skip
Buddhist logic. Of course, this is
considered so important that its nickname
is the Gate to Emptiness. It's so
important that every year for three months,
you stop everything. The whole monastery stops.
All the regular classes,
you understand? If you join a
special group, and you're going to study
topic number 3, you're going to study the
second school, the
sad school.  Primarily from the book of Chan
Chan, giving marketing,
I keep making this joke to see
if I don't want you to
embarrass me with someone talking about
Chandra Levy. In fact, I'd like to
start with a success we had yesterday
during the Candil offerings in
Singapore. It was so noble to make a
very good moment because I'm fed up with
chili, and luckily I had some
before they mixed it with
chocolate, and it was the best tofu I've ever
had. Every time you want to come
to me, you can come whenever you want to
make it. It's been my house, and I'll
pay you back for borrowing the money
here.
So we mixed it with a
chocolate cake, and I'm happy to report that
the checks almost made me vomit.
And when I tasted it, and the
class arrived here, I do
n't know how many of you had that
experience, but it was a very
invaluable lesson, and I hope that after
Gates and Michael leave, and you're
teaching your grandchildren, you tell them the
story of the tofu with
chocolate cake, and they never forget it.
So that's a great
teaching tool.  You should start with that.
You can repeat ten times that people
who don't read hippie stuff with
bartenders from 2000 years ago lived there. You can
repeat it over and over again, or you can just be
an adult with chocolate cake and
make that frame and deal with
that bad memory with that
bad action. Okay, it's very, very, much
more powerful. People do
n't forget.
So whenever you think of a
game like that or something interesting, do it.
And that's a bit of your job as a
teacher. I don't know what your culture is,
and you have your own. For example, in
Finland—and I don't know anything about Finland—
you have your own food.
So mix two things that taste
new together and have your students
eat it and get to your own thing.
So once we did something about
you, not in New York.
We did a plan. We fed everyone a
very sugary, heavy dinner.
Then we did meditation
after eating,
and everyone stayed together, and everyone
was happy. Then we announced that we did it
on purpose to show them
not to eat that food before meditating,
and actually, they got angry. People got angry
because you did that to us. I'm sorry,
but never  They forgot very
well
the years 21 to 25.
Sometimes they say the wind course plus
20 or 25 years, so from 21 to 25,
if you choose to go for a higher level of
gays, you're waiting to be examined
even if you don't want to go anyway.
You have to wait about two or three years
because there's a limit on the number of
gases that can be in each
monastery.
In each monastery, there are two
normal gases and advanced gases, so
sometimes they wait for someone to
die to give it to someone. It's yours
then, so you can wait more than ten years.
Sometimes, if you want a higher gadget, a
higher level of gays, to have that
you have to be examined in all the
monasteries, in all seven Cappa colleges. There
are two colleges, the
James Bond colleges and the Gandin colleges,
and then there are seven
grand colleges. Then you have to
appear before each college. I went
to the girls' college, but I didn't have to be
with all the others because then I would
know if I had a gay, so you can't
waste your time, and that's when you
can study.  Also, for example,
you can work harder, more Troyens, more on
Master James and how to interpret what
Buddha really meant, and that's a
typical period when you can, whenever you want,
where you can study
specific topics. There's another one I want to
mention called Circus Circus.
These are topics of number four,
which is Zhang to Maitreya, the Jewel of
Realization. And there, for example, mention
of the 12
Winsleys, the two links of dependence, and
the Wheel of Life in about ten
words, and that's all.
Then there's a custom of extracting
that line
and writing the whole book about that
line, and that's a world of difference. It means
extracting
the juice of a plant beforehand, as
medicine. The phases are the process of opening and
then squeezing until
you have the juice of the plant, and then you
use it as medicine. This means
extracting the juice of Maitreya
and then teaching it separately to
someone. So, there are five great tricks
in my monastery, for example. If you study
only one of them at that time, one
of them is called
Samsung, and it's basically the
Lion Dance, all the details of the
Lion Dance. One of them is the
dependent origination of the two.  One of the links
is
what all the possible
combinations of the five paths mean. There are
20 permutations. You're supposed to be
Kenyan x. They
give you the pen as a marginal Jana and
then record that plain mass.
It has 20 parts. It's like a mind map.
In 20 parts, how can you reach
enlightenment in different ways? And
what was clear is
that all the copies were lost in the
Cultural Revolution. They were all
burned, so we don't have them anymore, they're
lost. But John Brady's project was
found in Russia, and we covered them.
We finalized it, and that was the
first book printed on a
computer in Tibetan and in the world. It
was a two-volume set. We have
a trust in Donna, and I'm so
proud of that. It's amazing. I mean, if
there were a floor, I would have
done that thing for 30 years and spent
10 million dollars. It would have been worth it.
And there are many more. So anyway,
if you're waiting for your degree, and
there are many people who haven't died yet, your
class, then you have to go and do
son. And in the interpretation, Jansa,
or maybe you can do that, circus, okay?
And then every year in the winter, for
three months, you do logic towards school
number two because it's so important for
each subject that it's necessary for the
other subjects. So there's a custom
in Tibet
that's very cool, and every  Every year
for a month,
the monastery selects the 50
best candidates from different classes—
the fifty best students. This
team is here; it might be a mail-order.
Everyone packs their backpacks, a
sleeping bag, or a blanket and walks to the
monastery called Yang Rato. It's a
special little monastery in the
mountains,
and they debate together for a month.
Sometimes all day, sometimes all
night. Once a week it's all
night; you don't sleep, you debate all night.
So it's kind of like the Olympics of
debate. I mean, every year your
monastery debates sword hyung for
three years and three months, and the monks
prepare to go to the
winter debates for a month. They pass the
winter debates, and the guys aren't that
good, so they stay
and try to improve for the
next year. Then they can compete
to be on the team. So it's
very rare to go to One, to be selected
to go to One,
and I went to 4. I'm bragging because I
told the teacher, "I'm going to go even if you
select me. I don't know if you can do that,"
and I said, "I'm going to do it." So I
was like an equal, like 51,
and I'm very happy that I did.  I did it because
then I understood that I had many
realizations on that subject, so I
learned it and it was extremely difficult,
extremely difficult, because a debate
can go very fast and I was very
frustrated
when I taught course 13. I lost half
of my students in New York when
I taught logic; half left. I had
80, I was left with 40, 40 left,
and it's difficult, it's very difficult, and I decided that
not
something.
So don't be afraid, don't be
lazy, go for the difficult things.
This is the Son Capa tradition.
I became one of the best because I
only
remember being so angry and
frustrated. So after you do it, what
very well,
maybe we won't get to the class
very well. I would like to cover a few
more courses. Course number five is about how
karma works.
Someday someone will guess which one. One of the
same kind of motivations to put
that in the 18 fundamental courses. What do
you think?
And I said, as a Westerner, I'll
give you a hint:
if different countries have
the word karma, at least people talk
about karma a little, maybe some of that
superstitious talk, but at least you've
heard of karma. But in my  Culture, and in
Western countries,
I took the course for Westerners, almost
all European Americans,
Latin American citizens,
but I said, I think I'm going to put a course
on karma here so you can kind of
confirm the details of karma.
So in America, when I was
growing up, I remember my mom and I, I
remembered the first time I heard the
word karma, and by the way, in those
years, like 1835 in the 1950s, it was very
rare to hear the word karma,
but my mom, I don't know why, heard it, and
then I was killing insects in
our house, I was killing flies with
a newspaper, and my mom told me not to swat them,
because my mom said bad karma, what
is bad karma, and she said it's going to come back to you. I
said like, because where does it stay,
where does it go, where is it stored? And she said, I don't know,
like the teachers, like the moms who
say, don't ask so many questions.
So that's
the
American understanding of karma. It stops there, we don't
know where it goes, we don't know about
seeds. Some people say it's
like a boomerang that comes from two
miles away and then returns ten years later,
like  We have all these
strange ideas, this is... I thought there were
many strange ideas about karma in my country,
in my culture.
I should... we should learn from this. And
as I mentioned before, I think what
the student said is that they are capable and blessed
some people who live in countries that have
multilevel marketing or other countries or other places
where people learn about karma, where
karma has already been discussed, but
people don't understand it, they just believe it
because their mother believes it. So,
by the way, Pavón, we almost
got to the real class, or Manifas, better yet,
and he's going to talk about that tonight. Why do you do it just
because
your parents do it? And that's one of the reasons
why I put a karma course in at
that point because none of the
students grew up with karma, they didn't
understand the details. So, and I'm
very proud of that course.
It's how karma works
and it gives you all the details about
karma. So now, the sources,
you know, inhabit more things. The text of
this... read and we use a
lot of the commentary made on the soul,
but also the commentary of the first
Dalai Lama. So, he wrote a very
good commentary. Now, he was a young man...
When they are here for an old man, then
he only spent a few steps, just a few
years with his cloak, and I put a painting, a
picture of him,
and it's in the images of the 18
fundamental courses in the review, in the summary.
So, well, I like that picture. It's a
painting. I found a painting from the one
for you, the day I met his dad,
and he has a very funny mustache. I'm
sure here's the next one.
Because monks can't have a
mustache and beard, it's specific, and so we
are allowed not to have
hair on top, but don't let it grow down here.
So, we're going to try to find the
painting for you. This book, by the way,
is the best, the best biography of
Concapa in the world.
So, if you want to know more about your
own West lineage, just for
fun, it's not difficult. It's a
children's book, it's a book to entertain, and TV
is great because it has many pictures, and
Taipei is undoubtedly based on 50
famous paintings. It took me 15 years to
finish it. And if you really want to
know about Concapa's life, what I tell
people, well, at a
coffee table, at home, and every time  There are people who open
it. There's a great tradition in the
monastery that we open this
book on a
birthday, for example. If
Easter comes, shouldn't we
open it? Maybe this
Easter Sunday, we can open it. Just open it,
close your eyes, and kiss the prayer. It's a
message from Buddha and Saint Capac. The best
tradition, not Caine and Gary, since there's a
garden and they have it stimulated. They keep
writing
inside.
Resource number 6,
which is the diamond cutter shooter,
and you already know that,
right? And this has a
very interesting story behind it. It's
fun to tell you these stories
of how I wrote these courses. So, if you don't
study the Diamond Cutter Sutra
at the Saint Capac Monastery, it's not
part of the course, and it's a graphic. It's a
great truth
that I don't
think is right.
Many people don't study this,
so it's a shame that they didn't
study it. I
think I've already told you this story. There's
a community living in Mongolia
in a temple with 515 Mongolians,
and we used to go to the people's houses.
I think it's  The first day and then he
shaved, but we used his comment for the
life weapons. I translated it for about 12 years, I didn't
publish it, and I've already finished it. I wrote
a dictionary for life weapons, and it took me
about 10 years
on the bus. I spent the most four
hours a day
because I couldn't leave the monastery. So,
to the community, there are
recipes, some prayers, and they give you
food. Plus, the women who sing it
also give you a red hat. All
this because the monks have no
income. It was
a very poor community, a very
poor village,
and so it was very exciting
for the monks to have some money and
eat well. The book, and we all went. You're supposed to
recite things like that.
In Mongolia, the
diamond workshop is very respected; it's
considered very valuable.
I think in China too, in Japan, in
Vietnam. So anyway,
oh my, oh my, site, we needed the
Diamond Sutra.
3. Wait
a minute, he was a gay, blind, high-
level Mongolian, and he memorized it.
He took the sutra to families in their
homes.
In fact, he died. He
died with a role. I was already...  So,
five minutes, something we told him, okay, he
said nothing, let's
divide the writing,
all the pages, and we can eat faster, I
told him, but, but it's going to sound really
weird, so student, let's say
things, and phlegmatic, I don't know anything,
we always recited the
different pages, and I had the sexiest page,
close to two, then, and we found in
Russia Jones for the project, in fact, he
found the only Tibetan commentary, there's
only one, and those who are the ama
had a taste of Choni Lama
this morning, this lama, this law is a writer,
and we found the commentary and then we
digitized it, the commentary of cameras, and the one that
is also long, and we are
translating it, it's going to be like a thousand pages,
the shortest commentary, you add up, I
think, and it only has 30 pages, it's
shorter than the subway, so luck,
but anyway,
interesting for me,
personally, that among possesses, he got
sick, and the doctor said that he had to have
surgery, many hours ago, sitting
in the hospital with him, and I didn't have
much to do anymore,
I was in the middle of the curious, and there I
said to myself, hey, what do I do now? And he said, we have to
do the diamond workshop  And I saw
that it was there, it can't be
moved, so it has to answer the
questions. So I
started translating in the
hospital, and that's how I always
remember the sutra. So if someone
asks you what it is, how it flows from lunches,
but the hospital, those are the two. If
you want to make a good story to
study, the day she decided that everything
was taken care of before they went too
far, indicated in the course, and that's also
a very good reason. It's
fundamental and must have a very
good dose of emptiness. We've had the
highest middle path in the course so far.
Yes, about course 1, a third of
course 1, but there aren't any of the other
courses. So you haven't really
had a course of emptiness. So they are
now the best
firepatel.
There are others in other courses, but they are from the
lower middle school, and some
are also used for the higher schools.
So it's good to have a dose of the
culture of the diamond workshop, that
logic for course number 6. I'm going to
try to do two more today, and then we'll
also find a manuscript from
yesterday about diamonds in Russia, and some of
the things you don't know is that
John's team passed  14 years
in the library of Saint Petersburg at
the Russian Academy of Sciences of the
Eastern Division. 14 years passed and they just
made a catalog. They haven't even
digitized them yet, and hopefully we can put them all together.
This is just to
scan the many books of Don
Quixote.
We have to try to save them in case there's
a fire because Russians
love to smoke, and I've seen
things happen, fires happen.
So anyway,
we have permission to go to the library,
and when we catalog the books,
every time we do it,
every part of the book is here.
So if you search with your soul, there's only
one copy in the world, and they're from Burgos.
Time, and if Latin, it's time,
sir. It's in your hand. It's the manual. It's your
hand.
So the manuscripts all look the
same, to be honest. It
could be Blood, it could be Garbage
Andújar, but in Higüey. Anyway,
under the manuscript
it says, "You are made of lava," so I
was happy.
I think it could be a type of hat.
It seems that his hat looks like
Johnny's. Okay,
in action, no. So, as you know, the
next image,
you can only lower it if not
this.  The course became the
Diamond Workshop business book that
sold over a million copies and
is in 35 languages, and I think it's
interesting that the course, and if there is, it
became an intact book. So, 60, that's what it
started, it said, and it is already, in fact, so it's kind of
cool. Very well, I'm going to do two
more too. With that, I don't mind, I'm
just being polite and rude.
A Western, what is the course? Seven for
the Bodhisattva Vows. I was
trying to find a painting for
this, but it's very difficult,
but I did it. Do you want to go down a bit?
Team
Sandra.com. With my [unclear], he lived about 600 AD.
He wasn't a monk;
he was someone who had
lifelong vows. Laymen, and he wrote
many Buddhist vows, and we also
have vows from pride and some
other sources. And in this
Buddha course, we have four sources for the 64
vows. And I have
Chinese friends, Dr. Gu, who contacted me
recently and asked Lyon to
teach him
the vows because not all of that
transmission came to China in that form.
So it's very good to have [unclear].  246
sixty-four x 64 in total how many vows
roots and 18 and 46 18 roots 46
secondary and many other structures
there are many other vows associated
commitments but there is a book by that
Cappa called The Highway for the
Votes and CS for the Votes he
explains each vow on many pages they
spend many pages on each vow and
when that collection of scriptures the
most important of Tibet is printed
everyone puts that one first before this
first and there must be a reason so that's
why the list of the 11
the signified highway bus
back then we use that book now in
Cannes shooting again thanks to the
kindness of John Brady to 10 innings
incredible book called
The Strings of Jewels which before I
know
you have to be loyal to Toubon Asterio
but that was the point because I think the 10th
Dalai Lama
decided to write a book of vows they are
called Thompson said Thompson
there are signified three sets of vows
which are they number one are the
liberation vows 88 types of
liberation vows and then the  Bodhisattva
and then the tantric vows. So
if you write the monk vows, it's like
53 paragraphs to explain each vow.
And this is that glove. André Gide, the Israeli,
decided to write a book on all
three sets of vows, but he decided to make it
short. And sexy,
Lasarte catheter. I told him, "There are the
vows. Here is the vow correctly,
but short, and each one is like three
or four sentences." So he
decided to cover all the vows,
including the hundreds of them,
and wrote this beautiful, premium,
credible, and very well-written book. It's very well-written, very precise,
very accurate about the vows. We
should translate it. I'm just being
inspired by the teachings of Daimon
Montaigne. During the three-year retreat, he
taught the monk vows. Part of the
monk vows in this book,
by the way, was a very important teaching
and was overtaken by other events, but
that teaching was very important. So if
you find a recording,
especially if you want to be a nun, you
should study it. That's extremely
important. I was very happy with this.
So anyway,
we found half of his book and
half of the pages, and
we spent years looking for the jeeps.  - I helped
Wild out and we looked for the pages and
finally in many countries we found
all the pages, we found three
pages here, two pages there and
we put them together and finished it,
so we should give the man a round of applause
[Applause]
then I took the difficult boots,
I took the clarification of jets from the son
layer and in the easy ones they made a
hole of school,
the list, the middle way, the highest, the highest,
one more question and we go to
class,
in fact, in the monastery means,
hopefully, the same as already, the one that means, what does it
mean, and God willing, then sometimes
in some series, humanity
in home means, God willing, see,
maybe not very well, we're going to go to your
classes, don't worry, inshallah, and it
means, from vile Ariane, it's
related to Sanskrit and the word
which comes from there,
and we go to course 8 called Death and
the Realms, how to die,
where you can, what other options
after you die, what are the
places you can go,
and a friend of mine is dying today, they expect me to
die today,
and well, to know, maybe where you go is
good to be, so basically it's a
very good book about
When I was doing the courses, it
became very popular
to translate and study a book called
the Tibetan Book of Death.
Bardot is a Tibetan,
and it's very exotic, very sexy. Someone I
know, a friend, went crazy from
reading it. In fact, they put him in a
mental asylum. So he studied it with a
teacher
and liked it. It was like
a year in the
mental institution. So, the future
and sad bardo. Interestingly, that book is
wrong. The Tibetan Book of Death is wrong. It's not
authentic, okay, it's
not accurate. It's missing the
first quality. If you study the bardo of
life and other
authentic sources, it's not like that. And so
you can say, you might
want to tell people that that book
is not correct, it's not right, and
we don't study it, we don't use it. We
use it in life, things, and other
sources. And I thought at this
time that it would be good to give an
accurate description of what happens in the
bardo and when you die, without which of those
two options of where you will go. Okay, so
once you try the future lives in
Course 4, people are going to say, and
then where do I go?  to go later in that
future life, and again I was
operating from a Western culture
that didn't believe in future lives, so
first I had to sell, I had to
sell future lives, and then people are
going to ask me, so where am I going? It's the
same thing, the 49 days, what happens
then, so what is the spiritual world,
what is the bardo? So I decided to
write a course after proving
that there are other past lives, hopefully, rather, you
should help them go there.
Perhaps you're interested to know that many of
these courses were inspired by my
mother because when I first went to
study Buddhism in Asia, she already had
cancer and she was dying, and I
went to my mother and said, "She's dying,
and what should I do? Are
we going to teach her how to die?" I was a
seamstress and wasn't interested in
Buddhism,
and so I wrote to her from India, and in
those days there were no emails, it was a
two- or three-week email,
sometimes the letters of the
letters would arrive a year after writing. I
told her, "Come, you're going to lose, you have so much to
lose, and you're already dying." They took her out
of her school; it was an appointment at the
school, and she had  And then she had an
episode
in class and they told her the children
need their shifts, that she should just go
home, that she was at home
waiting to die, that's why I wrote to her, I told her to come, that she had to
lose, yes, so well,
now she had never traveled
outside the US and she was very
sick, we drove her
to the library in
the  back of the car, there it was
lying, so we didn't put it on the
wall, stuck to the wall, and they showed it
that for three months it's like dying. I
was so impressed, I said, "This is
very good, this should be a course
for everyone." So basically, this
course came from my next
personal experience, and I found it very
important that people should have
a correct description of what's going to
happen after it happens to you. So I
like this course, and that's
all. We use avid weapon, and we use it well
within the comment that I entered. Clichsters,
the next image, Team
Manda, I'm
going to change your name to you. Manda,
and there it is.
So it's also a book called
Temple. Say, I'll call you. So the
greatest book I wrote, everything in Tibet,
is Hunger and Chemo, which is the soft
yields. It's a very large layer. In English, it
would be like 10,000 pages, 108,000
pages if we translate Witness with
notes.
So, and rather, you might be
interested to know that the name was stolen from
an older book called Temo.
All the words are the same except the
first one, so the  Hunger Chemo
means the great book of the steps of the
path, we fear to mean the great
book in the steps of the teachings and
are campa stole the path, tried almost all
the subject material, we
call it a Lambdin product,
meaning primitive, super
early, the one from the time of the
fields a thousand years ago, it is the longest book
seen by those who will make a pass
there, I can tell you that in its text by
itself it is almost, it is perhaps 10 pages
and that is typical of the more, well,
poetry of those who give pill,
generally we don't see a book longer than
ten or twelve pages, this is the last
book of all the fields and it is a thousand years old
and it is quite a labyrinth, all of Buddhism,
incredible, very difficult to read, old,
four hundred years before they are able
and were lost in the world
after the cultural revolution, we
couldn't find it, James
helped me,
Jim Smith, James Smith, who was, he
is the head of JETs for many years and he
helped me and we found half of the copy
in Russia,
we found some pieces
and somehow ended up in Indonesia,
some pieces, so we put them
all together  We made a copy, people, and then we
printed it at the monastery. We
did it and saved it. The leader, and
many years later, when I
was writing the biography of [name missing], there's
a story, and [name missing]
is sitting with his
students and says, "I hope we can
find the subject, I hope we can
find this book that's lost
because it sounds very good." So they went to
look for it, they found it, and
they found the only copy from that time,
four years after it had been
written. And this painting is the
whole excited [name missing] and usually
you use [name missing], as much as
you like. One
wants, it's like 30 pieces of
incense, and when a [name missing]
arrives, like [name missing], then
everyone has a silk scarf or a
flower, you understand,
a red envelope. Here, the [name missing]
can give the largest [name missing],
and then you greet the great lama with
incense, some offerings, and
silk scarves. It's a custom. So
in this painting, the book is being
handed to a [name missing] and he does the
lama thing to him, and he's out there with
incense and a silk scarf to
put [name missing] in a book. He's treating the
book like a lama [name missing].  And that's what's
happening in this painting.
So I thought it would be more auspicious
to put something from that book
in your course. So I put it in the 21st course, "
Death and the Realms of Existence."
This course is translated from this book. It's very,
very cool. About three years ago,
Layla, a high lama, sent me a package and
said, "I have this thing from Tibet. I
think you'll want it. It's very rare."
And I opened it, and there was the Temple and Simon,
printed 20 years earlier. And I'm like, wow,
thank you so much. Okay,
and very good. That's a lot. See you.